<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.11">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>MagicDraw Component Plugin</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect1 id="index_1intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<para>This is the documentation for the Magic Draw UML to XML generator plugin.</para><para>Currently, the program can create XML files from component models and subsystem models. Subsystems within subsystems along side multiple instances of subsystems and models are supported. Additionally, exceptions are thrown if there is something the program cannot handle and error messages are displayed onto the console.</para><para>Notes <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>If there are multiple subsystems in a model, make sure to create a stereotype &quot;Top&quot; and assign it to the &quot;Top&quot; level subsystem. This will ensure proper naming of the XML files. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>A simple example of how to implement multiple subsystems and multiple instances of subsystems in a model can be found at tests/testMultipleSubsystems.mdzip.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Please make sure to give instances of subsystems unique names.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Velocity (<ulink url="http://velocity.apache.org/">an Apache template engine</ulink>) is being used to generate the XML files. These files can be found in the root of the MagicDrawPlugin folder and have .vm extensions.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1pluginUse">
<title>Using The Plugin</title>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Load a project into MagicDraw.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Ensure that the project either only has zero or one subsystems, or has the &quot;Top&quot; stereotype applied to one of the subsystems if many exist.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Click on the &quot;Component Autocoder&quot; tab in the top toolbar.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Click on &quot;Auto Generate Component/Port/Topology XML&quot;.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Check the MagicDraw console to see if any errors were generated.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>If not, the XML files can be found in &lt;projectDir&gt;/AutoXML/  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1programFlow">
<title>Program Flow</title>
<sect2 id="index_1menuConfig">
<title>Menu Configuration</title>
<para>These files take care of the menu configuration: <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_main_menu_configurator_8java" kindref="compound">MainMenuConfigurator.java</ref> - Creates &quot;Component Autocoder&quot; tab in the toolbar. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_xml_autocoder_action_8java" kindref="compound">IsfXMLAutocoderAction.java</ref> - Creates buttons within the &quot;Component Autocoder&quot; tab. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_about_8java" kindref="compound">IsfAbout.java</ref> - Creates the modal element that displays the about information. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_xml_action_8java" kindref="compound">IsfXmlAction.java</ref> - Action object that is called when &quot;Auto Generate Component/Port/Topology XML&quot; is clicked. Processes ports, components, and the entire topology. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_command_line_8java" kindref="compound">IsfCommandLine.java</ref> - Used to handle command line protocol. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_top_action_8java" kindref="compound">IsfTopAction.java</ref> - NOT USED. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_component_action_8java" kindref="compound">IsfComponentAction.java</ref> - NOT USED. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_load_i_d_config_action_8java" kindref="compound">LoadIDCOnfigAction.java</ref> - Creates button to load id configuration file within the &quot;Component Autocoder&quot; tab. <linebreak/>
</para></sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1objectProcessing">
<title>Processing</title>
<para><ref refid="_process_i_s_f_project_8java" kindref="compound">ProcessISFProject.java</ref> - Object processes both components and ports at the same time.</para><para><heading level="3">Component </heading>
</para><para><ref refid="_i_s_f_component_8java" kindref="compound">ISFComponent.java</ref> - Helper object for component processing. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_comp_xml_writer_8java" kindref="compound">IsfCompXmlWriter.java</ref> - Writes the processed components to XML documents.</para><para><heading level="3">Port </heading>
</para><para><ref refid="_i_s_f_port_8java" kindref="compound">ISFPort.java</ref> Helper object for port processing. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_port_xml_writer_8java" kindref="compound">IsfPortXmlWriter.java</ref> - Writes the processed ports to XML documents.</para><para><heading level="3">Topology </heading>
</para><para><ref refid="_process_i_s_f_topology_8java" kindref="compound">ProcessISFTopology.java</ref> - This object processes the model to create the topology XML diagrams. It can handle multiple subsystem within subsystems as well and multiple instantiations of subsystems and components. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_i_s_f_subsystem_8java" kindref="compound">ISFSubsystem.java</ref> - Contains many helper functions and objects used when process the model for the topology diagram. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_isf_sub_xml_writer_8java" kindref="compound">IsfSubXmlWriter.java</ref> - Writes the processed model to an XML document.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1exceptions">
<title>Exceptions</title>
<para>These are the Exception objects of this plugin: <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_component_exception_8java" kindref="compound">ComponentException.java</ref> - Thrown during component processing. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_port_exception_8java" kindref="compound">PortException.java</ref> - Thrown during port processing. <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_connector_exception_8java" kindref="compound">ConnectorException.java</ref> - Thrown during the topology processing <linebreak/>
 <ref refid="_load_i_d_exception_8java" kindref="compound">LoadIDException.java</ref> - Thrown during LoadIDConfig processing.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id="index_1otherObjects">
<title>Other</title>
<para><ref refid="_utils_8java" kindref="compound">Utils.java</ref> - Includes simple functions to help reduce code size (IE throwing ConnectorExceptions or raising warnings). <ref refid="_load_i_d_config_8java" kindref="compound">LoadIDConfig.java</ref> - Loads id configuration file into the model and over writes component base and window ids with ones found in the file.</para></sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1aboutDoc">
<title>About the Documentation</title>
<para>More resources can be found in the base MagicDrawCompPlugin/doc/ or at MagicDrawCompPlugin/README.txt <linebreak/>
 To update the documentation to reflect code changes: <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>This Introduction area can be edited in the top comment block in <ref refid="_main_menu_configurator_8java" kindref="compound">MagicDrawCompPlugin/src/gov/nasa/jpl/componentaction/MainMenuConfigurator.java</ref>.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Make sure Doxygen and Graphviz are both installed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Open the Doxygen Gui.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Under the &quot;File&quot; tab at the top, click &quot;Open&quot; and select the file titled Doxyfile in the MagicDrawCompPlugin directory.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Modify the settings (IE version number) in the GUI.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>To regenerate the documentation files, click on the &quot;Run&quot; tab in the GUI and click &quot;Run doxygen&quot;.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>To update the PDF found in the doc folder, go to doc/rtf and convert refman.rtf to refman.doc using Microsoft Word, and then convert the .doc file to .pdf.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1contact">
<title>Contact</title>
<para>Until the plugin is updated even further, I will be able to answer questions any time. My name is Saikiran Ramanan and I worked on the plugin as an intern during the Summer of 2016. My email address is <ulink url="mailto:saikiranra@gmail.com">saikiranra@gmail.com</ulink> </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
